<Document>
  # Thaven

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobThaven" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#808080]Thaven are [color=#b3b3b3]young adults[/color] until age 50, [color=#b3b3b3]adults[/color] until age 100, [color=#b3b3b3]middle-aged[/color] until age 150, [color=#b3b3b3]older[/color] until age 200, and [color=#b3b3b3]elderly[/color] beyond that point.[/color]

  ## Moods
  Thaven have a unique brain structure that's similar to a positronic brain, and thus have "moods" which affect them similarly to a borg's laws.

  All thaven naturally have and are effected by moods, through RP and sufficiently reasonable character building, the severity of moods may differ from character to character such as: An ion shielded skull dampening the effect of storms on the characters brain, a harsh regiment of mood stabilizers giving them a more even-keeled demeanor, or direct brain implants regulating the users emotional and mental state. Remember, the reasons for obtaining and having implants like these are expected to be realistic and grounded for the character and should not just be excuses to avoid playing out moods.


  [color=red]Note that a thaven's moods as written are non-diegetic gameplay features.[/color] They should be treated as things that have been integrated into your character's personality, and should not be referenced by their specific names or descriptions. You may choose for your character to be aware that their behavior has changed since their last shift, but they should not be able to recite exactly what is presented to you, the player. [color=#1e90ff]Thaven are, however, fully aware of this phenomenon, and may appropriately refer to them as "moods".[/color]

  [color=#ffa500]These moods should be followed to the best of your ability![/color] A mood being violated yourself or others can range from a small amount of discomfort all the way to a cascading mental breakdown. The specifics of that are up to you, but if a mood is violated, you should seek to correct the mistake as soon as possible.

  [color=red]Following your moods affords you a limited license to do certain things which would otherwise be against the rules, if approached with proper escalation. If you have a question about this, don't hesitate to ask using the AHelp feature (F1).[/color]

  ## Mood Swings
  Thaven brains are susceptible to fluctuations in electromagnetic fields. As a result, their ability to synchronize and regulate their moods tends to degrade with extended exposure to the cosmic radiation and ion storms that permeate space stations.

  While thaven naturally have moods, they also evolved to live in the protective magnetosphere of a planet. Life in space presents this unique challenge for them. How your character chooses to respond to this fact is up to you.

  ## Physiology
  The highly specialized endocrine system of the Thaven is capable of emitting a small amount of toxin from their skin, coupled with standardized defense courses in all Thaven hatching academies allows [color=#ffa500]their unarmed attacks to slowly build stun in their opponents by a mix of nerve pinching and toxin buildup.[/color]

  Due to sharing a common ancestor with space carp, thaven lungs are strange, resilient organs needed for blood circulation rather than gas exchange, so [color=#ffa500]inhaled gases have no effect on them.[/color] As such, [color=#1e90ff]thaven can safely breathe any kind of atmosphere,[/color] though unlike their genetic lineage, [color=#ffa500]they're still vulnerable to asphyxiation and barotrauma.[/color]

  Note that this also affects thaven undergoing surgery: [color=red]nitrous oxide won't work on them, and surgeons may have to resort to chloral hydrate.[/color]

  All thaven organs contain traces of neurons, and because of this, they take [color=#ffa500]10% more brute and cellular damage, and 20% more radiation damage.[/color] However, their unique ancestry allows them to take [color=#1e90ff]10% less heat, cold, shock, and poison damage.[/color]

  Like space carp, thaven flesh and organs contain carpotoxin. Their blood, while nontoxic, is [color=#ffa500]powerfully hallucinogenic.[/color]

  Thaven mature at the same age as humans, but they live roughly twice as long. Culturally, their lives are generally measured in fifths, with each being about fifty standard years long.


  ## Language
  Thaven speak Eckeckyik, a sing-song language quite similar to the calls and chirps of Earth's (now mostly extinct) dolphins and whales.

  The language consists of long vocalizations, clicks, chirps, and subtle manipulation of acoustic resonance to allow for clear communication while underwater. A large emphasis is placed on subsonic frequency and harmonics, making the language nearly impossible for other species to pick up.

  Outsiders often describe the language as a beautifully strange symphony of sound, though some label it as a blaring cacophony of annoying squeaking and squealing.

  And in every relevant language, the plural of thaven is thaven.

  ## Culture

  Due to their unique psychology Thaven culture differs wildly from group to group. While the vast majority of the Thaven population falls under Tau Ceti space, and thereby Biesel Government, a small few sects have held out across the further reaches of the territory.
  The remaining "Free Thaven" governments and civilizations are generally quite small, with some being dwindling technological giants to others remaining simple frontier kelp aquafarming villages. Within the last century and a half, the remaining "Free Thaven" governments have started to observe a sharp drop both economic and population growth, having been attributed to the growing scarcity of phoron, and a strange increase in the local sectors cosmic radiation levels causing increased instability among thaven youth.

  Shared across all Thaven population, isolationist frontier planets or Biesel's own Little Eckeyik district, is a great love for Kelp Pods! While the origin of the plant and how it has spread so far through Thaven culture is unknown, it remains a staple and beloved part of all Thaven households!
  Traditionally, the kelp pod is grown year-round for its medicinal properties, with small crops being used for fermentation and culinary purposes. Some deep sea villages have even been reported to selectively breed bioluminescent pods to be used as light sources!

  ## Thaven Naming Conventions

  Thaven typically name themselves after a single virtue they hold dear. Sometimes these names can be long and unwieldy.

  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Honesty
  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Have Mercy
  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Give Thanks To Thy Ancestors
  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Obedience
  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Search The Scriptures
  - [color=#449944]Appropriate:[/color] Always Hold Love In Thy Heart
  - [color=#994444]Inappropriate:[/color] John Smith
  - [color=#994444]Inappropriate:[/color] Fuck The Police
  - [color=#994444]Inappropriate:[/color] Live Long And Prosper
  - [color=#994444]Inappropriate:[/color] Always Be Diggin In Ya Butt

</Document>
